Guide to the Stanford University, Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research, Records SC0705
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research, records
1973-2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clayman Institute for Gender Research
Stanford University. Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research
SC0705
127.25 Linear Feet
Collection consists of records regarding the administrative affairs of the Institute and its programs such as conferences, classes, lectures (especially the Jing Lyman Lecture Series), and publications. Correspondence files of the Directors of the Institute include those of Iris F. Litt, M.D., Barbara Gelpi, Laura Carstensen, and Ineko Tsuchida. Also included are over 800 audiocassettes of seminars, talks, conferences, and lectures, 1973-2004.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research at Stanford University supports research on women's changing economic and social roles and organizes educational programs that make such work accessible to the public. It was originally founded in 1974 as the Center for Research on Women and later known as the Institute for Research on Women and Gender.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of records regarding the administrative affairs of the Institute and its programs such as conferences, classes, lectures (especially the Jing Lyman Lecture Series), and publications. Correspondence files of the Directors of the Institute include those of Iris F. Litt, M.D., Barbara Gelpi, Laura Carstensen, and Ineko Tsuchida. Also included are over 800 audiocassettes of seminars, talks, conferences, and lectures, 1973-2004.
Women -- Economic conditions.; Women -- Social conditions.; Women's studies.; Feminism.; Stanford University. Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research; Clayman Institute for Gender Research; Stanford University. Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research; Carstensen, Laura L.; Gelpi, Barbara Charlesworth.; Litt, Iris F.; Tsuchida, Ineko.; Stanford University. Center for Research on Women; Stanford University. Institute for Research on Women and Gender
- Audiorecordings, Accession ARCH-2004-126
  Scope and Contents note
  This accession contains audiocassettes (more than 800) of panels, lectures, meetings, seminars, and other events sponsored by IRWG, 1973-2004. A large number of the tapes are from the Jing Lyman Lecture Series, 1980-2004.
  - lecture: Speech at Canada College, 1973-11-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Snow: Women in Prison, 1973-11-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Women's Studies, 1974-02-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Johnston Reading at Stanford, 1974-03-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Martyna: Herstory of Women, 1974-05-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - CROW Group: Carl Degler--Women's History, 1974; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Howe--Women and the Power to Change, 1974-11-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Helene Rauch--Women in Medicine, 1975-01-22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Pat Nichols--Languages and Sex Roles, 1975-04-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Miller--Women in Developing Countries, 1975-04-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Bem--On Being the Male Half of an Equalitarian Marriage, 1975-04-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: [Molly] Gregory [filmmaker, teacher SFSU], [Susan] Elizabeth [news staff, KPFA], [Suzanne] Pingroe [PhD candidate, Dept. of Communication] & [Robert] Hawkins [Asst. Prof, Univ Wisconsin]: Women and the Media: Sexism in the news media, employment discrimination and a slide show on images of women in the media., 1975 July 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Marge Axelrod, Commission on the Status of Women--Women and the Media, 1975 July 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: The Law and Sex Discrimination--Recent Progress. Mary Dunlap, attorney and Elizabeth Colby, attorney. Favorable changes in interpretations of the law and the current status of the Equal Rights Amendment., 1975-08-3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Women Today: working towards equal/The Single Woman: problems and solutions. Tish Sommers, Coord. NOW task force on older women/ Guadelupe Hernandez, director of women's re-entry into Ed. Program, SJCC/Laurie Shields, Coord. Alliance for Displaced Homemakers/Lillian Moore, Analyst, Dept. Social Services, Santa Clara, 1975-08-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Women in the Labor Force: Issues and Action. Discussion about women seeking to improve the status of working women through unionization, 1975-08-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Lewis--Japanese Women in the Consumer Movement in Japan, 1976-04-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Arthur Wolf--Women in Traditional Taiwan, 1976-04-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Li--Marriage Law in China, 1976-05-5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Shishi Yobashi--Feminine and Feminism in Japanese Literature, 1976-05-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Sylvia Yanagisako--Changing Role of American-Japanese Women, 1976-05-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Eleanor Maccoby--Child-Rearing in China, 1976-04-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Cathy Lewis--Japanese Women in the Consumer Movement in Japan, 1976-04-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Estelle Ramey--Sex Hormones and Sex Ability, 1976-04-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Arthur Wolf--Women in Traditional Taiwan, 1976-04-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Victor Li--Marriage Law in China, 1976-05-5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Yobashi, Sheshi--Feminine and Feminism in Japanese Literature, 1976-05-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Lyman Lecture: Leah Chodorow--Why Study Women In Other Cultures?, 1976-05-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Lyman Lecture: Sylvia Yanagisako--Changing Roles of American-Japanese Women, 1976-05-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Bernard--Female Depression, 1976-10-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Porat--The Marriage Check-Up: Choosing a Lifestyle/Morgan - Alternatives in Mothering among 27 Black Families in Berkeley, 1976-10-6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Griswold--Sex Roles and Family Life in 19th Century America/Wald - The Legal Status of Women in the Family, 1976-10-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Cancian--The Impact of the Women's Movement on the Family, 1976-11-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Cook--Working Mothers -Part 1, 1976-01-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Cook--Working Mothers -Part 2, 1976-01-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Cook--Working Women's Problems, 1976-01-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Clossen--Sex Role, Achievement and Work, 1976-02-4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Middlebrook--The Ideal of Androgony, 1976-02-11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Collier--The Origins of the Family Reconsidered, 1976-02-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: McCloskey--Women at the Crossroads, 1976 Feb 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - lecture: Sandler--Women and Higher Education, 1976-03-3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Career Planning Symposium:, 1977-10-29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Career Planning Symposium:, 1977-10-29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Robert Hughs--Women in the New Music/Inkekes--Social Change in Developing Countries, 1977-11-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Middlebrook--American Women Poets/Ruotolo--Virginia Woolf, 1977-11-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Diane Fall Middlebrook--American Women Poets, 1977-11-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Robert Hughes--Women in the New Music, Nov. 121977; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Bridget L'Laughlin--Dvelopment in Mozambique: Women's Role, 1977-05-11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - National Conference: 1977 National Conference, 1977 June 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: De Bretteville--Feminist Culture/Peterson--Women Artists throughout History, 1977-10-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Raven--Georgia O'Keefe as an Artist/Yalom--George Sand, 1977 Oct 19, Nov 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Shaevitz--Coping Strategies for the Dual Career Couple, 1978 Feb 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Anne Peplau--Love and Power in Close Relationships, 1978-02-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Anne Peplau--How Men Affect Women's Achievement, 1978-02-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Victoria Fuchs--A Market Economist's View of Women Working for Pay, 1978 Feb 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - CROW presentation: Diane Middlebrook et al. GSO group, 1978 Mar 7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Tobias & Blum--Math Avoidance Lecture, 1978-04-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Wendy Smith--Women's Religious Quest, 1978-04-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Cissie Bonini--Women in the Judaic-Christian Tradition, 1978-04-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Dorothy Donnelly--Women in the Roman Catholic Church, 1978-04-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Nancy Tamler--The Jewish Woman, 1978-05-3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Diana Paul--Buddhism. Images of the Feminine, 1978-05-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Maccoby--Segregation in Childhood: How it Begins [Segregation by sex: the variable of gender], 1978-10-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Joyce Justus--West Indian Women Segregated and Isolated, 1978-10-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Strober--Women and Work: Movement, Stases, Research Issues, 1978-10-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Carol Dweck--Children and Sex Segregation, 1978-10-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Francine Blau -Occupational Segregation, 1978-10-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Michelle Rosaldo--Sex Segregation Across Cultures, 1978-10-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Eleanor Zuckerman--The Stress of Getting Ahead in Management, 1978-10-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Martine Reed--Piety and Role Models/Yalom - Adolescence, 1978-04-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Yalom--French Courtship, 1978-05-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Hellerstein -Childbirth/Yalom--Marriage and Adultery, 1978-05-8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Offen--The Mother Educator/Infant Mortality and Infanticide, 1978-05-15,16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Offen--Female Condition in 3 Cultures/Bell - Victorian Woman: Class and Culture, 1978-04-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Offen--Women in the Workforce/Hellerstein - The Rural Worker, 1978-05-22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Hume--The Factory Worker, 1978-05-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - lecture: Nigel Nicholson--Virginia Woolf: Letters and Diaries, 1977 Nov 30; 2.37; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Victorian Heritage I lecture: Hellerstein--The Female Child/Barbara Gelpi - Victorian Girlhood, 1978 Apr 11-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Myra Strober--Women and Work: Movement, Stases, Research Issues, 1978-10-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Joyce Justus--West Indian Women: Segregated and Isolated, 1978-10-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Francine Blau--Occupational Segregation, 1978 Oct 14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Michelle Rosaldo--Sex Segregation Across Cultures (2 tapes), 1978 Oct 14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Marilyn Yalom--French Courtship, 1978-05-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Estelle Freedman--The Household Manager, 1978-05-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Karen Offen--Women in the Work Force, 1978-05-22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Erne Hellerstein--The Rural Worker, 1978-05-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Leslie Hume--The Factory Worker, 1978-05-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - CROW task force: [meeting] (2 tapes), 1978-10-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Joan Talbert--Gender Workrole and Opportunity, 1978-10-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Cecil Reeves--Stresses in the Black Male, 1978-11-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Carmen Carrillo--The Chicana Experience, 1978-11-8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Norma Winkler--Sexism in the Classroom, 1978-11-15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Stephanie Brown--Alcoholism in the Workplace, 1978-11-22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Marion Sandler--How to Succeed (or Fail) in Business Through an Entrepreneurial Approach, 1978 Winter; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Ellen Dubois--The Suffrage Movement, 1979-04-9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Ellen Dubois--Stanton and Suffrage, 1979-04-11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Mollie Rosenham--Women in Revolutionary Politics, 1979-04-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Mollie Rosenham--Women in Revolutionary Politics 2, 1979-04-18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Myra Strober--Women and Economics [2 tapes], 1979-04-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Marilyn Yalom--Prostitution on the Streets and on the Stage, 1979-05-2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Ellen Dubois--The Economics of the Household, 1979-05-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Jane Collier--Sex and the Self, 1979-05-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Michelle Rosaldo--Female Sexuality, 1979 June 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Jing Lyman--The Family with the Non-Paid Worker, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Rhona & Harvey Weinstein--Dual-Career Families, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Marjorie & Morton Shavitz--Changing Relationships: Stresses and Successes, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - lecture: Howard & Nancy Tamler--Becoming Parents, Remaining Partners, 1979 Jan 20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - CROW group: Carol Idehlin [?], Eleanor Maccoby, 1978 Jan 9; 3.33; 1 audiocassette(s)
  - lecture: Ann & Robert DeBusk--Coping with the Stress of Sickness; Howard & NancyTamler--Becoming parents, remaining partners, 1979 Jan 20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Marilyn & Irvin Yalom--Loneliness and Intimacy, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Jo Freeman--Towards Economic Equality for Women (2 cc), 1979-10-3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Kay Mills--The Press and Feminism: The Making of an Issue (2 cc), 1979-10-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Maxine Waters--Public Policy Issues Affecting Minority Women (2 cc), 1979-10-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Karen Mulhauser--The Politics of Abortion (2 cc), 1979-10-31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Barbara Babcock--Women in Power (2 cc), 1979-11-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Maria Baeza, Cecilia Burciaga, C. Estreda--Policy Issues Affecting Chicanas (2 cc), 1979-11-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Nan Keohane--A Retrospective on Women in Authority, 1979-11-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Charlotte Bunch--Women as a Force in Political Change, 1979-10-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Cancer and Women, 1979-10-29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Linda Gordon--Domestic Violence (2 tapes), 1979-05-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Nan Keohane--A Retrospective on Women in Authority, 1979-11-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Carl Djerassi--The Politics of Contraception (2 tapes), 1979-10-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - CROW Retreat: [meeting], 1979 June 16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Women Poets in Translation (2 tapes), 1979-10-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Maryanne Horowitz--Aristotle's Women, 1979-10-29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Course summary, 1979 June 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Policy Board Meeting: [meeting], 1979 Sept. 26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Tillie Olsen--Gender and the Writer, 1979-01-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: American Audio Prose: Tillie Olsen interview, 1979-01-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: American Audio Prose 2 Tillie Olsen interview, 1979-01-17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Jing Lyman--Family with Nonpaid Worker/ Harvey & Rhona Weinstein--Dual Career Families, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Marjorie & Morton Shavitz--Changing Relationships: Stresses and Successes, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Al Young--Gender and the Writer, 1979-01-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - lecture: Barbara Christian--Gender and the Writer, 1979-01-31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - lecture: Janet Lewis--Gender and the Writer, 1979-02-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - lecture: Marilyn Yalom--Loneliness and Intimacy, 1979-01-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - lecture: Janet Lewis--[Gender and the Writer] copy, 1979-02-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - lecture: Susan Griffin--Gender and the Writer, 1979-02-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - lecture: Arturo Islas--Gender and the Writer, 1979-02-28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Renate Bridenthal - American Families in Flux, 1979 Apr 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: David Spiegel--Families of Mentally Ill, 1979 Apr 25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Panel "Is there a Family? New Anthropological Views"--Collier, Rosaldo, Yanagisako, 1979 June 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Eli Zaretsky--Family and the State, 1979-05-9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Claire Vickery--The Role of Housework, 1979-05-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Linda Gordon - Reproduction: Women and Family, 1979-05-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: William Goode--Why Do Men Resist?, 1979-05-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Spring 1979 lecture series: Rethinking the Family: Jessie Bernard - Re-Thinking the Family, 1979-05-31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: DuBois--The Suffrage Movement, 1979-04-9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: DuBois--Stanton and Suffrage, 1979-04-11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Rosenhan--Women in Revolutionary Politics (2 tapes), 1979-04-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Strober--Women and Economics, 1979-04-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Yalom--Prostitution on the Streets and on the Stage, 1979-05-2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: DuBois--The Economics of the Household, 1979-05-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Rosaldo--Introduction to the Family (2 tapes), 1979-05-9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Collier--Separate Spheres, 1979-05-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Yalom--Family and Sexuality, 1979-05-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Collier--Family, Society, and Self, 1979-05-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Collier--Sex and the Self, 1979-05-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Victorian Heritage II lecture: Rosaldo--Female Sexuality (2 cc), 1979 June 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Bea Whiting--The Company They Keep [cont. from Jan.8--group discussion], 1979-01-22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Yalom--Older Women in 19th Century, 1979-02-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Yalom--Older Women in 19th Century (tape 2), 1979-02-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Shelly Rosaldo & Jane Collier [talks], 1979-02-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Sylvia Yanagisako [talks], 1979-05-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Sylvia Yanagisako [talks] (tape 2), 1979-05-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Bea Whiting talk (tape 1), 1979-01-8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - CROW Group: Bea Whiting talk (tape 2), 1979-01-8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Shelly Rosaldo & Jane Collier [talks], 1979 June 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Shelly Rosaldo & Jane Collier [talks], 1979 June 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Barrie Thorne [talks], 1979-11-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Barrie Thorne [talks], 1979-11-12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Carol Jacklin--Biology and Social Policy [talks], 1979-11-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - CROW Group: Carol Jacklin [talks] (tape 2), 1979-11-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Robert Marcus--The Aging Skeleton and the Problem of Estrogen Replacement (2 tapes), 1980-01-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Geraldine Oliva--Family Planning, 1980-02-6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Pat Miller--Family Planning Alternatives & Health Care for Women, 1980-02-6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Stuart Agras--Anorexia and other Food Disorders, 1980-02-13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Netta Grandstaff--Breast Cancer: New Options in Care, 1980-02-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women and Health Care Lecture Series: Moira Fordyce--Geriatric Issues: Medical and Social Aspects of Care of Women, 1980-02-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women in the Second Half of Life Lecture: Jing Lyman--Living Longer Can Mean Living Better/ Lillian Rubin--Women of a Certain Age/ Lenore Weitzman--Divorce In Middle Age, 1980-03-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Women in the Second Half of Life Lecture: Lenore Weitzman--Divorce in Middle Age (cont'd.)/ Virginia Oleson--Ethical Issues in Estrogen Replacement/ Tish Sommers --Breaking Age Barrier, 1980-03-1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media View Women View the Media (CROW lecture series): Virginia Carter - The Image of Women in the Media: Vacuous Victims, 1980-04-9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series) Valerie Coleman - The Other Side of the Camera: The Politics of Women in Broadcasting, 1980-04-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series) Mercedes DeUriarte --The Gerber Baby Goes South, 1980-04-23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series): Diana Russell - Pornography and Violence Against Women, 1980-04-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series): Arlene Kaplan Daniels--Does the Women's Movement Influence the Media? A Trickle UP Theory of Dissemination, 1980-05-7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series): The Tabloid Collective--Institutional Obstacles to Creativity in the Media, 1980-05-14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - The Media Views Women View the Media (CROW lecture series): Lewenstein & Pfifer--Women's View of the Media, 1980-05-21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Post-Benefit Meeting (Book and Art Sale): [meeting] (2 tapes), 1980-05-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - Ronald Rebholz--Shakespeare's Women, 1980 Sep 5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)